<context_boundaries>
<core_topic id="bu-support-相關知識" title="BU Support 相關知識" path="/general/bu-support-相關知識.html">

1. Support Chip 資料
1. Flash 存取相關知識
1. Hub ISP Flow
1. PD ISP Flow
1. Code flow
1. Third chip ISP Flow
1.

</core_topic>
  <related_context>
    <related id="camera-透過我們驗證-code-sign" title="Camera 透過我們驗證 code sign" path="/code-sign/camera-透過我們驗證-code-sign.html">
    
    ### Camera
    1. generate ecdsa key & sign ecdsa key
    1. 告知如何Erase Camera 的方式 —> verify fail 要 erase 掉
    1. 告知如何 Read Camera data —> hub security model 必須要 read 到 update 的 data 才可以算出hash
    1.  2 , 3點 可以改成 告知我們所有的 update flow 以及相對應的文件，讓我們控制整個update 
    1. 下圖為Hub Code Sign 驗證 flow ，驗證code sign 應該Tool 就可以控制，FW 應該不用改甚麼，但是還是要麻煩俊太確認看看
    
    </related>
    <related id="code-sign-flow" title="Code sign Flow" path="/code-sign/code-sign-flow.html">
    
    ## Genesys Logic code sign overview
    因應客戶的需求，firmware 都必須要驗證合法性，目前做法是把bin檔做成hash，然後 用 private key 對 hash 做sign的動作產生signature(deliver signed firmware) 
    把 firmware bin data & signature & public key 傳送給security module，讓 security module透過 public key 對 signature做解密，產生hash ，然後再用firmware bin data 產生一組 hash ，互相做比對，來決定firmware bin是否合法(firmware update and verification)。
    code sign 的做法有下面幾種
    1. OpenSSL
    會把generate 出來的key pair 放在電腦裡面，deliver signed firmware 也是在電腦裡面完成的
    1. Token
    1. HSM (Hardware security module)
    A hardware security module (HSM) is a physical computing device that safeguards and manages digital keys, performs encryption and decryption functions for digital signatures, strong authentication and other cryptographic functions. These modules traditionally come in the form of a plug-in card or an external device that attaches directly to a computer or network server. A hardware security module contains one or more secure cryptoprocessor chips
    但是根據HP 規定要符合fips 140-2 level 3 以上，所以至少要用Token來達成code sign 功能
    fips 140-2 level 3
    > **Note:** In addition to the tamper-evident physical security mechanisms required at Security Level 2, Security Level 3 attempts to prevent the intruder from gaining access to CSPs held within the cryptographic module. Physical security mechanisms required at Security Level 3 are intended to have a high probability of detecting and responding to attempts at physical access, use or modification of the cryptographic module. The physical security mechanisms may include the use of strong enclosures and tamper-detection/response circuitry that zeroes all plaintext CSPs when the removable covers/doors of the cryptographic module are opened.
    目前Genesys Logic 使用的 code sign 演算法為Ecdsa nistp256
    ## Genesys Logic CodeSign flow
    1. generate key
    1. deliver signed firmware
    sign的動作如下，先把Data轉成hash 檔，然後透過eToken or Smart Card裡面的 Private key 轉成 signatute 
    1. firmware update and verification
    
    </related>
    <related id="hid-code-sign-update-rule" title="HID Code Sign Update Rule" path="/code-sign/hid-code-sign-update-rule.html">
    
    ## Protocol
    - 驗證方式只存在GLbinTool 以及 FW本身，ISP Tool只有做update data 動作
    - 不同Model 不能互燒
    - Flash 內沒有 signature 時，在ISP時要先用 Vender command 送。
    - Vendor Command 
    - 不能 run 的 code 不能留在裡面。
    ## HP ISP Flow
    - 說明
    - HID Code Sign Bin Format
    - HID Code Sign Bin Format (GL9511)
    ### Version 2.0
    - ISP Command ：Tool 會指定 Address 與長度並將整份檔案送下去，FW 需自己分析各資料位置。
    ## 驗證方式
    - 驗證 Public Key & Signature
    
    </related>
  </related_context>
</context_boundaries>